<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interpretable Deep Networks on The Visible Net</title>
    <link>https://thevisible.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interpretable Deep Networks on The Visible Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 18:12:34 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://thevisible.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>001 Catching Up</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/articles/001-catching-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 14:36:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/articles/001-catching-up/</guid>
      <description>Today I got an email from my good college friend David Maymudes. David got his math degree from Harvard few years ahead of me, and he I have both worked at Microsoft and Google at overlapping times. He is still at Google now. We have both witnessed and helped drive major cycles of platform innovation in the industry in the past, and David is well aware of the important pieces of work that go into building a new technology ecosystem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/articles/000-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/articles/000-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to The Visible Net, a blogging outlet for the “East-Coast Contingent” of mechanistic interpretability machine intelligence researchers.
Introductions. I am David Bau, an assistant professor at Northeastern University, and my lab focuses on understanding the interpretable mechanisms that emerge from large-scale machine learning. I am a late-career academic. I returned to finish my PhD at MIT several years ago, after two decades building products and leading product development for Google, Microsoft, and startups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>