<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Interpretable Deep Networks on The Visible Net</title>
    <link>https://thevisible.net/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Interpretable Deep Networks on The Visible Net</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 18:12:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://thevisible.net/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>American STEM Investments to Redirect</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/005-american-stem-projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 06:27:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/005-american-stem-projects/</guid>
      <description>For background on why these cuts are happening and what we can do about it, read the full story here.
How to Contact Your Senator The Senate is making these budget decisions RIGHT NOW. If you live in one of these states, your senator needs to hear from you immediately. Click on your senator&amp;rsquo;s name to send them a message asking them to redirect STEM funding to serve ALL Americans rather than cutting it entirely:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strengthening STEM in America</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/004-strengthening-stem-in-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 17:30:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/004-strengthening-stem-in-america/</guid>
      <description>Dear MAGA friends and all Americans,
I have been worrying about STEM in the US a lot, because right now the Senate is writing new laws that cut 75% of the STEM budget in the US.
Sorry for the long post, but the issue is really important, and I want to share what I know about it.
The entire funding for the NSF and NIH together is only 0.82% of the federal budget, but it is hugely important for science, funding the entire science research and education pipeline in the US.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A National Deep Inference Facility</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/003-national-deep-inference-facility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 17:30:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/003-national-deep-inference-facility/</guid>
      <description>Update: See the NDIF website for current information.
In October 2022, the White House Office of Science and Technology Policy released a Blueprint for an AI Bill of Rights delineating a consumer’s right to AI systems that &amp;ldquo;provide explanations that are technically valid, meaningful and useful.&amp;rdquo; In January, 2023, the National AI Research Resource Task Force identified one of the four critical opportunities for strengthening the U.S. AI R&amp;amp;D ecosystem as the development of trustworthy AI by &amp;ldquo;supporting research on AI’s societal implications, developing testing and evaluation approaches, improving auditing capabilities, and developing best practices for responsible AI R&amp;amp;D can help improve understanding and yield tools to manage AI risks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is Artificial Intelligence Intelligent?</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/002-is-ai-intelligent/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Apr 2023 17:30:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/002-is-ai-intelligent/</guid>
      <description>The idea that large language models could be capable of cognition is not obvious. Neural language modeling has been around since Jeff Elman’s 1990 structure-in-time work, but 33 years passed between that initial idea and first contact with ChatGPT.
What took so long? In this blog I write about why few saw it coming, why some remain skeptical even in the face of amazing GPT-4 behavior, why machine cognition may be emerging anyway, and what we should study next.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Catching Up</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/001-catching-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 14:36:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/001-catching-up/</guid>
      <description>Today, I received an email from an old college friend who asked about GPT models, RLHF, AI safety, and the new ChatGPT plug-in model.  A lot has been happening in the past few years, so here is a bit of a crash course on the current state of the large language model world, and what concerns me about it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/posts/000-welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 15:54:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/posts/000-welcome/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to The Visible Net, a blogging outlet for the “Academic Contingent” of mechanistic interpretability machine intelligence researchers, as well as an incubation space for the proposed National Deep Inference Facility.  And some introductions, from David Bau.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://thevisible.net/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 05:35:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://thevisible.net/about/about/</guid>
      <description>The Visible Net is a blogging outlet for the “Academic Contingent” of mechanistic interpretability machine intelligence researchers, as well as an incubation space for the proposed National Deep Inference Facility. It is a shared blogging space for students, collaborators, and others working on mechanistic interpretability.
Contact us at info@thevisible.net, or reach out to David directly.
This project was started by David Bau, an assistant professor at Northeastern University. David&amp;rsquo;s lab focuses on understanding the interpretable mechanisms that emerge from large-scale machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
